Lincy George

Data Analyst

Contact

Address

Ahmedabad, India 380061

Phone

9824054837

E-mail

mailforlincy@gmail.com

Skills

Advanced Microsoft Excel

PowerPoint Presentation

Basics of SQL

Basics of Python

Data Visualization

Tableau

Attention to detail

Teamwork and collaboration

Data Collection

Managing databases

Numerical data interpretation

Alteryx

Experienced Data Analyst with 6 years' of demonstrated history of working in the financial services industry. Skilled in Microsoft Excel, Sql, Python, Tableau and data analysis. Experienced in collecting, organizing, interpreting and disseminating various types of financial data. Energetic presenter and confident communicator with the ability to circulate information in a way that is clear, efficient, and beneficial for end user. Highlights of my career include quarterly awards for individual performance and many 'Season Champ' accolades.

Work History

2022-02 -Current

Consultant

Capgemini, Pune

- Aligned closely with business owners and employees to gather information and gain operational insight.
- Also Worked For Clients like "Vantage" for their data migration to cloud and also worked on tools like Snowflake.
- Currently working as a business analyst roles for the client "Willis Towers Watson", one of the key insurance sector player, for their simplification data storage project.
- Managed multiple deadlines across several businesses to meet dynamic needs of multiple clients.
- Currently working on tools like Varonis and Jira for data analysis.

2021-02 -2022-02

Compliance Analyst

Atyeti Inc., Pune

- Currently working on a project with PAT team of employees on their trading accounts compliance with Credit suisse compliance polices for their APAC region.
- Reviewed audit and monitoring reports related to consumer and client activities.
- Performed deep audits of PATs to assess compliance with Credit Suisse standards.
- Updated spreadsheets with latest data to enhance strategic planning.

2018-01 -2020-04

Data Researcher II

S & P Global, Ahmedabad

- Recognizing data issues and discrepancies from analysis and implementing remedial actions to ensure high level of data consistency of content/data for business entities.
- Data cleaning, De-duplication, validation, consolidation by reviewing data reports and indicators, Add/edit data as per process guidelines.
- Deliver on predefined individual and team targets including delivering outcomes with quality and excellence.
- Lead in error discussions of the team with
 Hyderabad counterparts for removal of errors of
 the team and reducing their error
 accountabilities with valid policies and
 procedures.
- Performed data management activities to ensure accurate, consistent, and complete clinical data by suggesting new error checks for error removal from the database.
- Worked with IFRS and US GAAP accounting standards of company's actual reported numbers.
- Trained new hires on the departments policies and procedures for updating data into the database.
- Have been selected for "Buddy Program" several times which help in smooth onboarding of the new hires.

2015-04 -2017-12

Data Researcher I

S & P Global, Ahmedabad

- Knowledge of databases from Cap IQ, Thomas Reuters and Bloomberg platforms.
- Been part of Legacy SNL and been among the first movers to S&P Capital IQ platform.
- Supported ad hoc requests from the Business and Senior Management in line with their expectations.
- Proficiency in spreadsheet/chart programs and tools like MS Excel, MS Powerpoint.

- Working knowledge of Data Visualization tools like Tableau and Power BI.
- Developed metrics, reports and statistics through data from annual reports and actuals reported numbers from the earnings of companies.
- Integral part of the doubt solving team for different processes of Cap IQ platforms.

2014-09 -2015-03

Analyst

S & P Global, Ahmedabad

- Conducting research to gather critical business information through creatively using sourcing techniques for internal and external databases such as Contributor reports, Annual Reports, SEC/SEDAR filings etc. and conducting qualitative analysis.
- Validated results and performed quality assurance to assess accuracy of data.
- Documented acquisition valuations and earnings accretion and dilution models for public and private companies.
- Documenting calculations and adhering to data management principles.
- Built and maintained databases for forecasting future financial performance.

Education

MBA: Finance

L.J. Institute Of Management Studies - Ahmedabad

Graduated with 7.14 GPA

B.Com: Accounting

Prin. M. C. Shah Commerce College (Navgujarat) -Ahmedabad

• Graduated with 70% of marks

Certifications

Tableau essential Training

Tableau essential Training

Basics of Python

Accomplishments

- Awarded "Quarterly Individual Excellence"
- Awarded "Long term service reward" (LTSR)
- Felicitated with "Season's Champ"

.